

JOAQUIM MAURÍCIO TELECOMMUNICATIONS CONSULTANT

OBJECTIVE

Experienced in field support, my main goal is to learn and evolve as a technician, possibly transitioning to a programmer position.

Main interests include automating repetitive tasks to accelerate processes and make them more reliable

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Web Design (HTML/CSS/JavaScript)
- Some programming bases (mainly Python)
- Cisco and Huawei equipment knowledge
- Very comfortable with Nokia equipment solutions

CONTACTS T (+351) 919079424

E jpsmauricio92@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

ALTRAN PORTUGAL, NOKIA

JUNF 2018 – ON-GOING

Started as a consultant analyzing radio sites through photos and documentation using knowledge acquired while working on the field, suggesting changes and making corrections to technical documentation.

Currently on an Acceptance Team, checking radio sites and approving/rejecting sites, according to their on-site status.

WONDERCOM, NOS PORTUGAL

DECEMBER 2017 – JUNE 2018

Provided remote assistance to technicians on the field, and applied configuration to mainly Cisco and Huawei equipment to migrate the services of Millennium BCP to NOS.

Used different platforms like SolarWinds and BMC Remedy to register and track equipment installed.

REDITUS, ERICSSON

FEBRUARY 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

Front Line Maintenance for NOS Portugal, kept responsibilities from past position and started being on call 24/7, having to respond to SLAs.

REALLIFE TECHNOLOGIES, NOS PORTUGAL

AUGUST 2012 – FEBRUARY 2017

Maintained HFC, FTTH and MSC networks, providing support for Cisco, Juniper, Arris, Motorola and other hardware brands. Coordinated small teams in the scope of expanding such networks.

JOAQUIM MAURÍCIO TELECOMMUNICATIONS CONSULTANT

EDUCATION

POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE OF SETÚBAL

HR Management - Not Completed

SANTO ANDRÉ HIGH SCHOOL

Technician in Business IT

Course mainly devoted to programming and database management. Used HR tools like PRIMAVERA and Colibri.

SOFT SKILLS

Strong communication skills acquired from weekly presentations of project status, and constant communication with the client.

Provided training about Nokia Equipment Solutions, through which I've learned how to make myself clear.

Currently helping coordinate the documentation and acceptance team where I'm inserted, creating and presenting weekly reports.

Passionate about acquiring knowledge and learning different methodologies and technologies.

Always trying to detect troubles that may appear in the workplace and responding with the appropriate action.